<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Learn another day (Posts about software development)</title><link>https://al1s.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link type="application/rss+xml" rel="self" href="https://al1s.github.io/categories/software-development.xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2018 &lt;a href="mailto:alstof@gmail.com"&gt;alstof&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 13:26:43 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>My 60 Second Pitch</title><link>https://al1s.github.io/posts/pitch/</link><dc:creator>alstof</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm a software development engineer, finally. I have already been a journalist, an analyst, an automation engineer, a data engineer. I have experience of managing support and development engineers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've triggered and authored a company's knowledge base which is still in use as a set of introductory tutorials and as a reference for troubleshooting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a long time, I've been a part of the operation team for a big payment service provider and troubleshooting became my second nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And all this integrated experience is a base and a source for my future career which will eventually lead me to the role of a system engineer or software architect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm adventurous by nature and consider risk and surprises as challenges I was given to learn and become better. The journey I've started at the beginning of August here in Code Fellows is fun and I'm excited to see what is the next chapter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to thank you, Aaron and Allisa, for being supportive and open to discussion, ready to dive into the project and share your ideas about functionality and user interface. One of the stretch goals was to create a user-friendly app so UX was among the active parts that shape the look and feel for the app.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>software development</category><guid>https://al1s.github.io/posts/pitch/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 13:19:14 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>