<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Learn another day (Записи о Final project)</title><link>https://al1s.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link rel="self" href="https://al1s.github.io/ru/categories/final-project.xml" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>ru</language><copyright>Contents © 2018 &lt;a href="mailto:alstof@gmail.com"&gt;alstof&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 21:59:04 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Plan and done for August-17-2018</title><link>https://al1s.github.io/ru/posts/plan-and-done-for-august-17-2018/</link><dc:creator>alstof</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;div class="section" id="what-will-i-learn-today"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What will I learn today?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol class="arabic simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practicing Javascript, git and workflow at CodeFellow.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="done"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Done&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have another final project idea: it's a site for tourists of Seattle with a main page, where you see only a bunch of photos of different tourists attrations. You can roll it (like a grand spinning wheel) in different ways (swipe on mobile?) depending on your platform and get a random photo. If it's something interesting - the user can click on it and get the more visual and text info about the place with a link to (or an actual) google maps. Another functionality is to let user keep and her notes about the place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Product name: Tourist Roulette&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;User stories:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a user, I want an app to provide me with tourist attractions in Seattle, so that I could choose where I want to go next on route.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a user, I want to be provided with a randomly picked place, so that I always have a choice without any efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a user, I want to have an ability to get some details about a chosen place, so that I could decide whether I'm interested in it or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a user, I want to have an ability to get the place position on a map, so that I could plan my trip in details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a user, I want to have an ability to leave my private notes on attraction I've attended, so that I could later share them with my friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a hiring manager, I want to know about the guys who created the app, so that I could assess their skill set and get an expression of their abilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a developer, I want to face a challenging task, so that I could feel the pleasure of accomplishment when I would overcome the challenge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;## Stretch goals&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a user, I want all the features to be presented in a game form, so that it was fun to use the app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a user, I want to see current weather conditions in Seattle, so that I could plan my trip with all information available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a user, I want to see how far the chosen place is from my current location, so that I can decide whether to go there or to find something closer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a user, I want to be able to share my impressions about the place I've visited immediately into all well known platforms, so that I could spend less time to open and publish into each app separately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MVP&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The user can get a random picture of the tourist's place in Seattle on the main page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The user can click (touch) on it and get the page with a description, additional photos and a google maps link.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The user can get&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stretch goals:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class="simple"&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to make it roll&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google map attached to each page about a place.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to edit/print/save to file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A scheduler to make a planning and set notifications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What should we author?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CSS classes hierarchy
Shareable data objects format&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid>https://al1s.github.io/ru/posts/plan-and-done-for-august-17-2018/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 22:30:31 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>